<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-23T17:09:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Notes</title><subtitle>Mostly words, a few pictures.</subtitle><author><name>Daniel Jay Hartman</name></author><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/welcome-to-jekyll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-11-19T23:05:18-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-19T23:05:18-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/welcome-to-jekyll">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Daniel Jay Hartman</name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dinojump</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/dinojump" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dinojump" /><published>2017-03-17T00:00:37-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T00:00:37-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/dinojump</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/dinojump">&lt;p&gt;I got the urge to code a game recently, so I made a simple clone of &lt;a href=&quot;https://chromedino.com/&quot;&gt;Dino Runner&lt;/a&gt;, the hidden game on the page that Chrome shows you if it’s unable to connect to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dj/dinojump&quot;&gt;repository is here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to check out the code or run it by downloading the Love application for your operating system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pickingluaandlve&quot;&gt;Picking Lua and LÖVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know much about game development, but I felt like I wanted something high level and portable. I wanted to learn a new language, because most of the “web” languages I’m familiar with (JavaScript, Java, Python, Ruby) aren’t used much in game development (besides sometimes JavaScript, but usually as a compile target).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was vaguely aware of Lua’s use as a scripting language used in games, and I wondered if it was common to build entire games with it. I liked the idea of a fast, interpreted language. A simple tool for a simple game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While studying Lua (reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lua.org/pil/&quot;&gt;Programming in Lua&lt;/a&gt;, watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EQhlp6rCrY8&quot;&gt;conference talks&lt;/a&gt;, making this game) I get the impression that people don’t really Lua as the main language of a game for much beyond the occasional indie or toy game, but a toy is exactly what I wanted to make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lua is a small, simple and fast language with a nice syntax. Spending most of my time at work in JavaScript, it’s hard not to wonder about an alternate universe where Lua was the scripting language of the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://love2d.org/&quot;&gt;LÖVE&lt;/a&gt; is a very small, minimal game development framework for Lua, exactly the kind of easy to pick up tool I was looking for. I’m not sure I’d stick with it if I wanted to make a more complicated game, (same goes for Lua), but it was exactly what I needed to get started making a game quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finishingforthesakeofit&quot;&gt;Finishing for the sake of it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to get better at finishing projects that I start and putting them on the internet instead of letting them sit in my dev folder for years until I delete it years later because there’s no way I’m sharing that silly project I never finished from years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Daniel Jay Hartman</name></author><summary type="html">I got the urge to code a game recently, so I made a simple clone of Dino Runner, the hidden game on the page that Chrome shows you if it’s unable to connect to the internet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Going to College</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/on-going-to-college" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Going to College" /><published>2015-05-02T00:00:04-04:00</published><updated>2015-05-02T00:00:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/on-going-to-college</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/on-going-to-college">&lt;p&gt;Advice I wish I could go back in time and give to 17-year-old me. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t rely on people who have a vested interest in you enrolling in their institution to educate you about debt. Do it yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritize your time between classes. You will make mistakes, but stay focused on the classes that matter most to you. Sometimes, you just have to do what you can to get through a class so that you can focus on another class.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Above all else, prioritize your long term health and wellbeing. You always have time to get some exercise, eat regularly and sleep if you make it a priority.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting up early is awesome. You’re always being more alert and prepared than everyone else. Staying up late is overrated.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prioritize people who put their time in you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t compare yourself to other people, especially at school. You have no idea what paths have brought both of you here, and can’t meaningfully compare the two.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t be afraid to change your major. It’s a lot less painful than getting a college degree you don’t want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate the little things, five years is a long time to delay gratification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Daniel Jay Hartman</name></author><summary type="html">Advice I wish I could go back in time and give to 17-year-old me. Your mileage may vary.</summary></entry></feed>